Guide to the Stanford University, Black Community Services Center, Records SC0369
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Black Community Services Center, records
1973-1988
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Black Community Service Center
SC0369
0.75 Linear Feet
Correspondence, memoranda, proposals, questionnaires, programs, publications, and flyers pertaining to the activities of Black students at Stanford and the history of the Center. Other Black groups represented include the Black Recruitment and Orientation Committee, Ujamaa House, Joint Center for African Studies, Stanford African Student Association, Stanford Black Pre-Medical Organization, and Stanford Out of South Africa.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Transfer, 1989.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Black Community Services Center is a division of the Dean of Student Affairs. It initiates and coordinates Black student involvement in community service programs and provides primary advising and support services for Black Voluntary Student Organizations.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, proposals, questionnaires, programs, publications, and flyers pertaining to the activities of Black students at Stanford and the history of the Center. Other Black groups represented include the Black Recruitment and Orientation Committee, Ujamaa House, Joint Center for African Studies, Stanford African Student Association, Stanford Black Pre-Medical Organization, and Stanford Out of South Africa.
African American college students; Stanford University; Stanford University. Black Community Service Center; Stanford University. Dean of Student Affairs; Stanford University. Black Community Service Center; Stanford University. Black Community Service Center
- Records
  - Afro-American Studies (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ASSU packet, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Black Community Retreat, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - BCSC GRAPEVINE and calendar, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - BCSC letterhead (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - BCSC miscellaneous information handouts (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BCSC original proposal, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - BCSC Packet (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - BCSC Packet, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Black Executive Committee, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Black Liberation Month, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Black Recruitment and Orientation Committee, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Black Student volunteer Center, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Black Theme House (Ujamaa) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Flyers, 1978 and 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Flyers, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Flyers, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Flyers, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Flyers, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Flyers, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Flyers, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Flyers, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Flyers, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Flyers, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Joint Center for African Studies (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Day, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. International Freedom Games, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous brochures, non-Stanford (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Stanford information handouts and brochures (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - “Opportunities for Black Students,” circa 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Stanford African Students Association, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Stanford Black Community Caucus, newsletter 1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Stanford Black Pre-Medical organization (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Stanford Out of South Africa, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - “Survival: A Resource Book for Native American Students,” 1976 (Box 2, Folder 26)